Finding aid for the Marsha Epstein Papers LSC.2220
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1970; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 29, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1971; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 29, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1973; printed paper, handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 29, Folder 12)
- Programs, 1962-1998; printed papers (Box 29, Folder 13)
  Contains programs for professional and academic ceremonies.
- Travel materials, 1977; printed paper, clippings (Box 30, Folder 1)
  Includes journals, travel guides and documentation from Marsha Epstein's travels to Sri Lanka, Pakistan and London.
- Correspondence, 1983-2011; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Research materials (miscellaneous), 1985-2007; printed paper, photocopy (Box 30, Folder 3)
  Research materials focused on the health system in California and various disease prevention programs.
- Taxes, 2006; printed paper, photocopy (Box 30, Folder 4)
  Tax information for Marsha Epstein, reports, receipts and summary financial details.
- Egypt, 2007; clippings, printed paper (Box 30, Folder 5)
  Travel and tourist information, labeled by Marsha Epstein as "Egypt."
- Homeowner's insurance, 2009; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 30, Folder 6)
  Includes policy information and duplicates.
- Postcards, No date; postcards (Box 30, Folder 7)
  Souvenir postcards from Marsha Epstein's travels.
- Legal materials, 1966-1968; printed paper (Box 31, Folder 1)
  Contains information concerning liability of physicians and medical professionals.
- Our Bodies Ourselves, 1970-1971; newsprint (Box 31, Folder 2)
  Birth Control Handbook 12th edition Women and Their Bodies by Boston's Women Collective
- Research materials (miscellaneous), 1970-1990; printed paper, photocopy (Box 31, Folder 3)
  Miscellaneous medical and professional research materials.
- Research materials (tobacco), 1973-2009; printed paper, photocopy (Box 31, Folder 4)
  Contains research materials concerning tobacco, addiction and cessation programs.
- Duty statements, 1981-1997; printed paper, photocopy, handwritten notes (Box 31, Folder 5)
  Duty statements from the Department of Health and associated agencies.
- Flyers, invitations and programs, 1991-2012; printed paper, photocopy (Box 31, Folder 6)
  Contains flyers, invitations and programs for cultural events.
- Drugfree workplace program, 1999; printed paper, photocopy (Box 31, Folder 7)
  Information and notes from a Drugfree Workplace Program.
- Certificates and diplomas, 2004; printed paper (Box 31, Folder 8)
  Includes: City of Hope Appreciation Certificate Los Angeles Public Health Leadership Institution Cohort IV Certificate of Completion "Working Together - Getting to the Core of Public Health" Certificate of Appreciation of Vaccine Administration Trainer
- Souvenirs (Egypt), 2007; printed paper, postcards (Box 31, Folder 9)
  Souvenirs from Marsha Epstein's travels to Egypt.
- Letters of recommendation (from Marsha Epstein), 1971-1975; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 32, Folder 1)
  Letters of recommendation for students, coworkers and employees by Marsha Epstein.
- University of California Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1972-1980; handwritten notes, printed paper (Box 32, Folder 2)
  Internal memos and notes between medical professionals.
- Correspondence, 1972-2011; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Classes (taken by Marsha Epstein), 1976; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 32, Folder 4)
  Lists of classes taken by Marsha Epstein and the years taken.
- Holiday letters, 2003-2012; printed paper, photocopy (Box 32, Folder 5)
  Holiday letters from various friends and family of Marsha Epstein.
- Organizational correspondence, 2005-2012; printed paper, photocopy (Box 32, Folder 6)
  Inter-office correspondence, memos and flyers.
- AL-ANON and ALATEEN, 1985-2012; printed paper (Box 32, Folder 7)
  Information from twelve step groups, flyers for events and meetings.
- Medical services for Latinos (cultural competency), No date; printed paper (Box 32, Folder 8)
  Research materials and information on medical services for the Latino community.
- Certificates (training and continuing education), 2004-2010; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 32, Folder 9)
  Certificates from professional development programs.
- Readers and educational materials, 1970-1973; printed paper, photocopy, folders (Box 33)
  Marsha Epstein's readers from medical school.
- Correspondence, 1980-1999; handwritten notes, envelopes, notecards (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 2000-2013; handwritten notes, envelopes, notecards (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Research materials, 1970-1989; printed bound books, photocopy, printed paper (Box 35)
  Contains Toastmasters materials, The Psychology of Addiction, Assessment and Management of Dementia and various research materials on liability and specific ailments and diseases.
- Ephemera, 1970-1990; t-shirts, framed plaques, magazines, clippings, newsprint, handwritten notes (Box 36)
  Contains clippings, diaries, framed awards and plaques and t-shirts from various events and activities within the medical and activist communities.
- Photographs, 1995; color photographs (Box 37, Folder 1)
  Family photos with Marsha Epstein, her son and extended family.
- Reed College administrative information, 1962-1965; typewritten paper (Box 37, Folder 2)
  Administrative and registration information for Marsha Epstein's time at Reed College in Portland, Oregon.
- Reed College class notes, 1962-1965; handwritten notes (Box 37, Folder 3)
  Notes from several undergraduate courses taken by Marsha Epstein at Reed College in Portland, Oregon.
- Anytown, USA, 1962; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 37, Folder 4)
  Notes, handouts and workshop information from a week long course for young community leaders.
- Malpractice insurance, 1978-1996; printed paper (Box 37, Folder 5)
  Research and documentation related to malpractice insurance for Marsha Epstein's medical work.
- Disability insurance, 1987; printed paper (Box 37, Folder 6)
  Disability insurance policy information and correspondence.
- Lesbian News correspondence, 1990; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 37, Folder 7)
  Contains a draft of a letter to the editor of Lesbian News.
- Vehicle and registration information, 1997-2006; printed paper (Box 37, Folder 8)
  Contains all information related to vehicle registration and insurance.
- Correspondence, 1997-2000; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 37, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, predominantly from Seymour, all personal correspondence.
- Research materials (stress), 1998-2001; printed paper, photocopies (Box 37, Folder 10)
  Contains research materials related to stress and effects on health.
- Work notes (miscellaneous), 2000-2010; handwritten notes, photocopies (Box 37, Folder 11)
  Contains miscellaneous work related notes not organized with other papers.
- Work notes (miscellaneous), 2000-2010; handwritten notes, photocopies (Box 37, Folder 11)
- Meetings with Dr. Prieto, 2006; printed paper (Box 37, Folder 12)
  Correspondence, memos and documentation of work related grievances between Marsha Epstein and a supervising physician.
- Research materials (tobacco cessation), 2008; printed paper (Box 37, Folder 13)
  Materials related to programs for tobacco cessation.
- Roybal Center, 2009; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 37, Folder 14)
  Surveys developed for the Roybal Center around tobacco use and other health concerns.
- Tobacco cessation (Burbank), 2009; printed paper, photocopies (Box 37, Folder 15)
  Workshops, talks and other programming oriented around tobacco cessation.
- Tobacco cessation (programming), 2009; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 37, Folder 16)
  Programming, talks, correspondence and logistical information for various tobacco cessation programs throughout the greater Los Angeles area.
- Ephemera, 1980-2010; various (Box 37, Folder 17)
  Awards, buttons and t shirts from various events honoring the medical profession and Marsha Epstein.
- Job search, 1993-2004; printed paper (Box 38, Folder 1)
  Contains documentation from various job searches over the years, resumes, applications and letters of support or interest.
- Divorce, 1998-1999; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 38, Folder 2)
  Various documents relating to the divorce of Marsha Epstein and Tariq Mahmood including correspondence. Wendy Herzog acted as Marsha Epstein's attorney.
- Research materials (obstetrics), 1961-2000; printed paper, photocopies (Box 38, Folder 3)
  Research materials related to obstetrics, focused on the psychological and psychiatric aspects.
- Journals, private documents, 1972-1983; handwritten notes (Box 38, Folder 4)
  Personal writings and journals of Marsha Epstein.
- Rashad Mahmood, 1997-2012; printed paper, photocopies, handwritten notes (Box 38, Folder 5)
  Various documents related to Marsha Epstein's son with Tariq Mahmood, Rashad Mahmood. Documents concerning his schooling as well as summer activities and personal correspondence are included.
- Miscellaneous, 1945-2000 (bulk 1945-1960); newsprint, printed paper, laminate (Box 39)
  Contains newspaper clippings as well as personal calendars and some photographs.
- Greeting cards, 1970s-1990s (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
- Photo negatives, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
- Resumes, c. 1990s (Box 40, Folder 4)
- Autobiographies, resumes, and job applications, 1970s (Box 40, Folder 5)
- Ephemera, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
- Weekly planners and address book, 1974, 2003 (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Los Angeles County American Medical Women's Association: Directory of Women Physicians, 1979-1994 (Box 41, Folder 1)
- National Women's Health Network Resource Guides, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Health articles and notes, 1980s-2000s (Box 41, Folder 3)
- Prison health: Medical care, 1971-1974 (Box 41, Folder 4)
- Jewish Community literature, 2013-2014 (Box 41, Folder 5)
- Jewish Genealogical Society, 1970s-2000s (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Imago, 2000s (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Health literature, 1970s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
- Health literature, 1970s-1990s (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1970s-2000s (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Clippings and research materials, 2008-2011 (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Picket slide rule, 1960 (Box 43)
- Class photos, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 43)
- Sisterhood Bookstore, West Los Angeles: Tote bag, undated (Box 43)
- Rashad's elementary school handprint project, May 1986 (Box 43)
- Awards and certificates, 1991-2007 (Box 43)
- Book: Women in White: Their Role as Doctors Through the Ages, 1972; (43 boxes) (Box 43)